Matthew B. Bowler

1210 North 16th Street Jacksonville Beach, Florida 32250 Phone: 904-351-8487
Portfolio Site: <u>matthewbbowler.com</u> Email: <u>mbowler03@gmail.com</u>
Github: github.com/mbowler03 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matthewbowler03

SUMMARY

A seasoned finance professional with over 20 years experience in Mortgage Banking and Community Development with the added technical skills of a FullStack Web Developer. A lifelong learner that is able to bridge any technical gaps and assist companies to lead in an extremely competitive and technology driven world.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

BROWSER BASED TECHNOLOGIES: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, Bootstrap

SERVER SIDE DEVELOPMENT: MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

DATABASES: MySQL (Workbench), MongoDB (ROBO 3T)

DEPLOYMENT: Heroku, Git, Github

PROJECTS

Hacker Scrape- https://github.com/mbowler03/news-scrape and https://cryptic-forest-75876.herokuapp.com)

This was built with Javascript, Node.js, MongoDB and uses Mongoose, Cheerio, and Axios NPM Packages.

Friend Finder-(https://github.com/mbowler03/friend-finder and https://agile-woodland-24429.herokuapp.com)

This was built with Javascript, Node.js, Express.js.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Owner, North Florida Healthy Vending

2018 to Present

• Owner of several healthy vending machines located in various private and charter schools in Jacksonville, Florida

Loan Officer, BBVA Compass Bank

2018 to 2019

Loan Officer to four BBVA locations in Jacksonville, Florida

Senior Loan Officer, Carrington Mortgage Jacksonville, Florida

2015 to 2018

- Closed over 23 million in FHA and VA mortgages in 2016 becoming one of the companies leading producers
- Obtained the promotion of "Senior Loan Officer" during the first month of eligibility by closing an average of over 14 loans per month since date of hire

2013 to 2015

- Specialized in the management of the transportation needs of large retail clients
- Solicited new business obtained from paid sales leads, research, social media, and referrals

Loan Originator, PHH Mortgage Jacksonville, FL

2011 to 2013

• Originated Mortgage Loans under Private Label Solutions for a variety of companies including: Charles Schwab, Merrill Lynch, E*Trade, TIAA-Cref, Ameriprise, and Keybank

Executive Director, Riverside Avondale Development Organization Jacksonville, FL

2006 to 2011

- Supervised all business activities, including staff, finances, production, marketing and sales
- Secured a minimum of \$125,000 per year in grants and donations annually
- Increased housing production by 300%, expanded service boundaries, and conducted all predevelopment activities for two future signature projects

Vice President, Operation New Hope Jacksonville, FL

2000-2006

- Conducted research and repair of property titles including removal and payment of liens and assessed taxes
- Purchased more than sixty properties in the downtown Jacksonville area through grants and lines of credit
- Assisted in raising funds for the organization through grant writing and tax credit submissions
- Sold and marketed all existing housing inventory

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

Certificate of Completion from 24 Week "Full Stack" Coding BootCamp

University of North Florida Jacksonville, FL

• Bachelor's Degree of Business Administration- Business Management

LANGUAGES

Spanish

• c1 fluency level- certificate obtained from Simon Bolivar Language School Cuenca, Ecuador